Guide to the Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1834-1980 CAM.NEV.1987.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Music, 1881-1903; I.
  - Published works by Nevin, 1.
    - Instrumental Works, D.
      - Narcissus, 1925 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 45)
        Narcissus / Trans. by Jascha Gurewich Boston: Boston Music, 1925 1 score ([6] p.); 32 cm. For saxophone and piano with a saxophone insert [in B flat].
      - The Rosary, 1911 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 46)
        The Rosary / Words by Robert Cameron Rogers, Arr. by Modeste Alloo. Boston: Boston Music, 1898, 1911, 1914 1 score ([4] p.); 32 cm. For trombone and piano [in E flat].
      - Gondolieri (arr. by Hugh Gordon), 1936 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 47)
        Gondolieri / Arr. by Hugh Gordon: for woodwind quintet. Philadelphia: The John Church Company, 1936 6 scores ([15] p.); 29 cm. For Flute, Oboe, Clarinet, Horn, and Bassoon [multiple keys] Included: score and parts for Flute, Clarinet, Oboe, Horn, and Bassoon.
      - Gondolieri (Gondoliers) (arr. by Hugh Gordon), 1936 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 48)
        Gondolieri / Arr. by Hugh Gordon; for woodwind quintet Philadelphia: John Church Company, 1936 6 scores ([15] p.); 29 cm For flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Horn in F, and Bassoon.
      - The Rosary (arr. for violin by Fritz Kreisler), 1917 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 49)
        The Rosary /Arr. by Fritz Kreisler. Boston: Boston Music Company, 1917 1 score ([1] p.); 29 cm For violin [in D] Notations penciled in/Mounted in a sheet music binder
        Also mounted in this binder - Narcissus / Arr. by Gustav Strube. G. Schirmer, Jr., 1899 1 score ([1] p.); 29 cm. For violin and piano [in A flat] Dedicated to Theodore M Fliney[?]
      - Narcissus (arr. for organ by R. Goss-Custard), 1910 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 50)
        Narcissus (From "Water SCenes") / Trans. by Reginald Goss-Custard Boston: Boston Music Company, G. Schirmer, 1891 and 1910 1 score ([6] p.); 32 cm For organ [in D flat] mounted in a presentation folder
      - Narcissus (arranged for orchestra by Gary Strube), 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 51)
        Narcissus / Arr. by Gustav Strube Boston: Boston Music, G Shirmer, Jr, 1899 10 scores ([11] p.); 25 cm. Orchestra parts [in D flat]: 1st violin 2nd violin Viola Bass Flute Clarinet Solo in B flat [hand written] 1st Clarinet in B flat Cornets in B flat Trombone and piano accompaniment Op. 13, no. 4
  - Manuscripts by Nevin, 2.
    - Songs, A.
      - A Folio of Sketches A51, 1899-1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 52)
        A Folio of Sketches A51 11 Scores [17] p.; 34 cm. pencil sketches in a bound folio [No. 1] Ein Heldenlied, [1] p.; 34 cm. [in A flat] [No. 2] Ein Ledchen, [4] p.; 34 cm. [in D flat], 11/27/1899 [No. 3] The Four Seasons, [2] p.; 34 cm. [in B flat], 2/16/1900 [No. 4] A Song, [1] p.; 34 cm. [in E flat] [No. 5] Untitled, [1] p.; 34 cm. [in F] [No. 6] At Rest, [2] p.; 34 cm. [in G], New Haven, 11/17/1900 [No. 7] Mighty Lak a Rose, [2] p.; 34 cm. [in F] [No. 8] Untitled, [1] p.; 34 cm. [in G] [No. 9] The Thrush, [1] p.; 34 cm. [in A] [No. 10] The Fireman, [1] p.; 34 cm. [in A flat] [No. 11] The Woodpecker, [2] p.; 34 cm. [in G] Includes notations and corrections in pencil.
      - A Folio of Sketches A53, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 53)
        A Folio of Sketches A53 5 Scores [17] p.; 34 cm. pencil sketches in a bound folio [No. 1] Napoli, [2] p.; 34 cm. [in D], (Original Napoli 1885) Edgeworth, 8/29/1899 [No. 2] The Nightingale and The Rose, [2] p.; 34 cm. [in E], Alvin Harvey-King, Washington D.C., 8/31/1899 [No. 3] Nightingale's Song, [3] p.; 34 cm. [in A flat], Edgeworth, 8/31/1899 [No. 4] June Night in Washington, [4] p.; 34 cm. [in A], Edgeworth, 8/1899 [No. 5] Quest (may be Guest, unable to verify), [6] p.; 34 cm. [in G], Last page cuts off in middle of sentence and song. No other pages found. Includes notations and corrections in pencil. Two pages of folio have been ripped out, those pages contained music notation, but not enough remains to determine song title, key, or other relevant information.
      - Apple Blossoms, 1880c. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 54)
        Single sheet folio of Apple Blossoms, [2] p.; 37 cm. [in A flat] Notations and corrections in pencil. Appears incomplete. No date is given on folio, date derived from first publishing date for Apple Blossoms.
      - My Love's Waitin', 1898c. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 55)
        A single sheet folio of My Love's Waitin', [1] p.; 37 cm. [in F] No date information is given, date derived from known publication date. Folio is dog-eared and fragile. Notations and corrections in pencil.
      - Folio Setting of Emily Warren's "Daisy", 1870c. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 56)
        A single sheet folio setting of Emily Warren's poem "Daisy", [2] p.; 37 cm. [in E flat] No date information is given, date derived from known publication date of the poem. Folio has two strips of silver tape on the back. Notations and lyrics written in ink.
      - Untitled, 1890c. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 57)
        Untitled folio with no lyrics. Notations in pencil. [1] p; 27 cm. [in D flat]. Folio has an ink blot in the middle of the page near the bottom obscuring some notations.
      - Folio of sketchbook, 1890 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 58)
        Unbound folio of A Sketchbook Holograph in ink, fair copy, with engraver's marks in pencil. Op. 2. [No. 1] Gavote. [2] p; 34 cm. For piano [in g]. [Dedicated] to E.F.B. Bottom of first page has "B.M.G. 88-100" written in ink. Also found in the middle of the bottom of the first page is "Copyright 1888 by G Schirmer Jr.
        [No. 2] Im Wunderschönen Monat Mai/ Text: Heine. [2] p.; 35cm. For voice and piano [in G flat]. [Dedicated] to E.F. With Eng. Tran. In pencil. Folio was exposed to water at some point and is smudged in places obscuring notations and lyrics.
        [No. 3] Love song. [2] p.; 34cm. For piano [in A]. [Dedicated] to W.C.S.
        [No. 4] Du bist wie Eine Blume/Text: Heine. [3] p.; 27 cm. For voice and piano [in G]. [Dedicated to E.D.N. Elizabeth Nevin Standish]. With composer's signature pasted on. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh by Mrs. Elizabeth Nevin Standish, as indicated by accompanying information card.
        [No. 5] Berceuse. [1] p. 35 For piano [in A flat]. [Dedicated] to C.W.S.
        [No. 6] Lehne deine Wang' an Meine Wang'/ Text: Heine. [2] p.; 35 cm. For voice and piano [in G flat] [Dedicated] to E.S.P. With Eng. Tran. In pencil. Folio has been smudged, perhaps while ink was still wet obscuring some notations and lyrics.
        [No. 7] Serenata [3] p.; 27cm. For piano [in a]. [Dedicated] to P.R.O.
        [No. 8] Oh, that we two wee Maying/Text: Kingsley. [2] p.; 35cm. For voice and piano [in A flat]. [Dedicated] to A.P.N. With composer's signature pasted on. The word "Kingsley" is written in pencil in the upper left of the first page. Folio is accompanied by front and back cover pages provided by the American Art Association Anderson Galleries, Inc. in New York. Front cover page states Autograph of Ethelbert Nevin From the Collection of Autograph Ms., "Oh! that we two were Maying." Back cover page contains a excerpt from the will of Edmond De Goncourt (translated) regarding the establishment of the Anderson Galleries.
        [No. 9] Valse-Rhapsodie. [4] p.; 27 cm. For piano [in C]. [Dedicated] to P.C.O.
        [No. 10.] Songs from "A Child's Garden of Verses" by R.L. Stevenson. For coice and piano. no. 1 ["In winter I got up at night"]. [1] p.; 35 cm. [in G]. [Dedicated] to F.R.Mc.A. no. 2 Singing. [1] p.; 34 cm. [in E]. [Dedicated] to E.F.H. The words "R.L. Stevenson" are written near the bottom of the page in ink. no. 3. [Dark-brown is the river]. [3] p.; 34 cm. [in G flat]. [Dedicated] to M.F.A. The words "R.L. Stevenson" are crossed out at the top of the page.
        [No. 11] The night has a thousand Eyes/[Text:] Mrs. Hermans. [2] p.; 27 cm. For mixed voice quartet with vioin obligato [in F]. [Dedicated] to W.I.N. Has the number 13 circled at the top of the page, indicating that two pieces may be missing from the sketchbook.
      - Doris: pastorale/Text: Arthur Munby (A7), 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 59)
        [Doris: pastorale]/ [Text: Arthur Munby] 1 score ([16] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy. For voice with orchestral accompaniment [in F] Op. 3, no. 3. Howard no.: A7 No date information given, date derived from publication date.
      - Doris: pastorale/Text: Arthur Munby (A8), 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 60)
        Doris: pastorale/Text: Artur Munby 1 score ([12] p.); 36 x 27 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy, with corrections and blue pencil marks. For voice with orchestral accompaniment [in F]. Op. 3, no. 3. Howard no.: A8. No date information is given, date derived from publication date.
      - Doris: pastorale/Text: Arthur Munby (A9), 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 61)
        [Doris: pastorale]/[Text: Arthur Munby] 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete sketch. For voice with orchestral accompaniment in F. Op. 3, no. 3. Howard no.: A9 No date information is given, date derived from publication date.
      - Herbstgefühl (Autumn Sadness)/Text: Karl Gerok, with English trans., 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 62)
        1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink. For voice and piano [in A flat]. [Dedicated] to Fraulein Clothilde von Finck. Op. 5, no. 1. At end: Oct. 27, 1888. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh by Mr. Slack. B.M.C. 115 Copyright by G Schirmer Jr.
      - Serenade from Ruy Blas (La Chanson des Lavandieres), 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 63)
        Text: V. Hugo -- 1888. 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Holograph signed, with additions in pencil. For voice and piano. [Op. 5, no. 2.] At end: Oct. 20th, '88 B.M.C. 114 Copyright by G Schirmer Jr.
      - Raft Song A35, 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 64)
        Scope and Content notes
        1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. [Op. 5, no. 4]. Published: Boston, Boston Music. Howard no.: A 35
      - Raft Song A36, 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 65)
        1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete sketch. [Op. 5, no. 4]. Published: Boston, Boston Music. Howard no.: A 36
      - In a Bower/Text: Louise Chandler Moulton, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 66)
        1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, with corrections and engraver's marks For soprano or tenor and piano [in e flat]. [Dedicated] to Mrs. Walter C. Wyman. Op. 12, no. 3. Howard no.: A 20
      - Little Boy Blue/Text: Eugene Field - Dedicated to W.S.O., 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 67)
        1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. Holograph sketch, in ink, with red pencil markings. For soprano and tenor and and piano [in B flat] Op. 12, no. 4 [Dedicated] to W.S.O. B.M.C. 149 Copyright 1891 by G Schirmer Jr.
      - Little Boy Blue/Text: Eugene Field, 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 68)
        1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Holograph sketch in pencil, incomplete. For soprano and tenor and piano [in B flat]. Op. 12, no. 4. Donated to the University of Pittsburgh by Gustave Schirmer, January 1935/On back: sketch in ink [of another composition?].
      - The Quest (Part 1 and 2): The Lady of Saville/Text by Randolph Hartley, 1902 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 69)
        1 score (46 p.); 34 cm. Holograph signed in ink, with corrections in blue pencil and additions in pencil. For chorus and piano. On p. 38: end part 1, Vineacre March 12th 1900. P. 39-45, part 1: empty. P. 15-17, part 2: empty. Published: Cincinnati, John Church, 1902. Howard no: A 53
        Part I Complete 2 pp of part II Howard A 54
      - Rappelle-Toi!, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 70)
        "Rapelle-Toi:" for mezzo sop. or for tenor with accompaniment of strings, four horns and harps. [1] p.; 32 cm. Title page only. Holograph signed in ink [Op. 17, no. 3].
      - Every Night/Text: Robert Louis Stevenson, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 71)
        1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano. [Op. 20, no. 3]. Howard no.: A 11.
      - Book of Songs, 1891-1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 72)
        A Book of Songs 11 scores, [48] p., 36 cm. [No. 1] Airly Beacon/Text: Rev'd Chas. Kingsley (Quincy, 1889) [in E flat], holograph in ink with notes in blue and red pencil. A correction was put in place with two straight pins, which have been removed for archival purposes. Correction includes notation in pencil. Op. 20 no. 5 - Quincy 1891 [No. 2] When the Land was White [Key is unlcear] Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano. Op. 20, no. 5 Howard no. A 48. [No. 3] A Song of Love/Text: Edmond Lock Tomlin, Holograph in ink, with notes in blue and red pencil. Copyrighted by G Schirmer, Jr. in 1893 - Paris 1891. Includes cover from the American Art Association Anderson Galleries. [No. 4] Nocturne for Piano & Voice/Text: T. B. Aldrich. Holograph in pencil, with notes in blue pencil, incomplete sketch. Op. 20, no. 7. Howard no. A 33 - Florida 1893, Copyrighted by G Schirmer, Jr. 1893. [No. 5] Dites-Moi/Eng Text: Mrs. O. Boise. Holograph in ink with notesin blue and red pencil. [In E flat]. Copyrighted by G Schirmer, Jr. in 1893. Op. 20 no. 8. - Manchester 1893 [No. 6] Orsola's Song (Chantez! la nuit sera breve)/Eng. version by Dr. T.R. Baker. 2 copies, on is a Holorgraph in ink and the other is a Holograph in pencil, unfinished. For voice and piano. [In A] Op. 20, no. 9. Howard no. B 20. Copyrighted by G Schirmer, Jr. in 1893. - Paris 1892. [No. 7] In der Nacht (In the Night)/Text: Graf Platen. For voice and piano [In B flat]. Holograph ion ink with notes in blue and red pencil. Copyrighted by G Schirmer, Jr. in 1893 - Berlin 1892 [No. 8] Nocturn. Sketch in pencil, incomplete. [In F]. Howard no. A33 [No. 9] In the Night/Text [German]: Graf Platen; Eng. trans. by Nathan Haskell Dale. Holograph sketch, with correction in pencil. With text on typescript laid in, with pencil corrections. Op. 20, no. 10. Howard no. A 21 [No. 10] Sleep Little Tulip/Text: Eugene Field. Op. 20, no. 2, Voice with piano accompaniment. Holograph sketch in ink with notes in blue and red pencil. Copyrighted by G Schirmer, Jr. in 1893. Accompanied by cover page from the American Art Association Anderson Galleries and a note card with metadata. - Manchester 1893 [No. 11] A Fair Good Morn/Text: [Not credited] Op. 20, no. 1. Holographic sketch in ink with notes in red and blue pencil. Copyrighted by G Schirmer in 1893. Accompanied by cover from American Art Association Anderson Galleries. - Manchester 1893
      - A Necklace of Love/Text: Frank L. Stanton, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 73)
        1 score ([5] p.): 34 cm. Holograph in ink, with engraver's marks. For contralto and piano [in E]. [Dedicated] to Irene Gibson. Op. 28, no. 1. In poor condition - ripped. Accompanied by cover from American Art Association Anderson Galleries.
      - Sleeping and Dreaming A40, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 74)
        [Text: Robert P. Nevin] 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano [in C]. [Op. 28, no. 2]. Published: Cincinnati, John Church. Howard no.: A 40.
      - Sleeping and Dreaming A41, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 75)
        [Text: Robert P. Nevin] 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano [in C]. Published: Cincinnati, John Church. Howard no.: A 41.
      - Mon Desir/[Eng. words: Jaques Ahrem] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 76)
        1 score, 2 copies ([11] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, with cut and paste and engraver's marks. For voice and piano [in c#]. Op. 28, no. 3. Published: Cincinnati, John Church, 1899. Howard no.: A 52. First copy is in poor condition and has been pieced together with adhesive tape in the past. Second copy is incomplete. Accompanied by Cover from American Art Association Anderson Galleries and a note card with metadata.
      - The Nightingale's Song/Text by Alvin Hovey-King; Italian trans. by Alice F. Schmall - high voice, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 77)
        The Nightingale's Song (Canzone del' Usignuola)/Text by Alvin Hove-King, Italian trans. by Alice F. Schmall. 1 score ([7] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy, with engraver's marks in red and blue pencil. For high voice and piano - original key, low voice F [in A flat]. Op. 28, no. 4 Dedicated to Madame Nellie Melba Score is accompanied by a cover folder from the American Art Association Anderson Collection
      - The Nightingale's Song/Text by Alvin Hovey-King; Italian trans. by Alice F. Schmall - low voice, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 78)
        The Nightingale's song (Cazone del' Usignola)/ Text by Alvin Harvey-King, Italian trans. by Alice F. Schmall 1 score ([7] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy, with engraver's marks in red and blue pencil. For low voice and piano - transposed key [in F]. Op. 28, no. 4. There is a stamp in purple ink on the first page saying, "Please correct this proof and return it to The John Church Co. Cincinnati, O."
      - The Nightingale's Song (Cazone del' Usignola)/ Text by Alvin Harvey-King, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 79)
        The Nightingale's Song (Cazone del' Usignola)/ Text by Alvin Harvey-King Title Page Only Howard Number A30 Stamped in purple ink, "Please correct this proof and return it to The John Church Co. Cincinnati, O."
      - [The Nightingale's Song] A31, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 80)
        The Nightingale's Song 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano [in A flat] Text set to both English and [Italian]. [Op. 28, no. 4]. Howard Number A31
      - [The Nightingale's Song] A32, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 81)
        Nightingale's Song 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano [in A flat]. Text set to both English and [Italian]. [Op. 28, no. 4]. Howard no.: A 32
      - Ein Heldenlied, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 82)
        Ein Heldenlied/ Text: Heine; Eng words: J. R. M. 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy, with corrections and engraver's note in red ink. For voice and piano [in A flat]. Op. 28, no. 7. Dedicated to A.F.N. Two stamps in purple ink on first page say, "Please correct this proof and return to The John Church Co. Cincinnati, O." Howard no.: A 19.
      - An African Love Song/Text: Paul Laurence Dunbar, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 83)
        An African Love Song/Text: Paul Laurence Dunbar 1 score ([5] p.); 33 cm. Holograph signed, in ink, incomplete fair copy, with pasted-on corrections. For soprano or tenor and piano [in d]. [Dedicated] to Mrs. Minnie Madderne-Fiske Accompanied by a cover from The American Art Association Anderson Collection, and an informational typed notecard with lot information from an auction.
      - At Night/[Text: Mary Baldwin], 11/6/1897 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 84)
        At Night 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Facsimile of holograph signed, in ink, with lyrics in verses at the bottom of the music. For voice and piano [in E flat]. At end: With love to Mary Baldwin's little ones from Ethelbert Nevin, New York.
      - At Rest [Titled: To Rest]/Text by Frank L. Stanton, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 85)
        At Rest [Titled: To Rest]/Text by Frank L. Stanton 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph signed, in ink [in G] Accompanied by a cover from The American Art Association Anderson Galleries, and a auction lot information card on the score.
      - The Fireman/Text: Frederick Manley, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 86)
        The Fireman/Text: Frederick Manley. 1 score ([1] leaf): 34 cm. Holograph signed, in ink, with pencil Marks. For voice and piano [in A flat]. The text in typescript laid in, 2 p. Howard no.: A12
      - The Owl/Text: Rebecca B. Foresman, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 87)
        The Owl/Text: Rebecca B. Foresman 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy. For voice and piano [in A flat]. Howard no: A 38.
      - The Owl A39, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 88)
        The Owl 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, fair copy. For voice and piano [in A Flat]. Howard no.: A 39 Music on last page does not seem related to first page. Accompanied by modern yellow lined paper with notes on this score
      - Sleeping and Dreaming - Multiple Sketch Folio, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 89)
        Folio with multiple sketches. The folio is bound together with thick metal clips. The last few pages are torn in half with the bottom halves missing.
        1) Sleeping and Dreaming 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano [in C]. [Op. 28, no. 2]. Howard no.: A42
        2) Dreaming While Sleeping 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For voice and piano [in C]. [Op. 28, no. 2].
        3) Untitled 1 score, incomplete, consisting of a measure and two notes. Holograph in pencil [in C].
        4) Sonata 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. Ethelbert Nevin signed his name at the bottom of sketch in ink. For piano [in C].
        5) Sleeping and Dreaming 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch, For voice and piano [in C]. [Op. 28, no. 2]
        6) [Wanderings O'er] 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch, For voice and piano [in A flat]
        7) Untitled 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch, For piano [in E flat] Page is torn in half with bottom missing
        8) [July] 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch, For piano [in E flat] Page is torn in half with bottom missing
      - Song of the Brook A44, 1890 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 90)
        Song of the Book 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete sketch. For piano [in G] [Op. 7, no. 4]. Howard no. A44
      - [When All the World is Young, Lad] A46, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 91)
        [When Al the World is Young, Lad]/[Text Chalrels Kingsley]. 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete. For voice and piano [in E flat] Howard no.: A 46
      - When All the World is Young, Lad A47, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 92)
        1 score ([1] p.); 26 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete fair copy. For voice and piano [in A]. Howard no: A47
      - Wynken, Blynken, and Nod/[Text: Eugene Field], 1890 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 93)
        Wynken, Blynken, and Nod 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete. For chorus and piano accompaniment. Howard no: A 49.
      - [O'er Hill & Dale] Bound Folio of sketches A50, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 94)
        [O'er Hill & Dale] Bound Folio of sketches A50, 4 score ([10] p.); 33 cm.
        [No. 1] Twas a Lover and His Lass, 1 score ([3] p.); 33 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For piano [in A flat], [Part of suite: O'er Hill & Dale]. Signed August 10, 1900
        [No. 2] An African Love Song/Text: Paul Laurence Dunbar. 1 score ([4] p.); 33 cm. Holograph, in ink, sketch, with corrections. For soprano or tenor and piano [in d]. [Dedicated] to Mrs. Mimie Madderne-Fiske. The text in typescript attached. Signed August 13, 1900
        [No. 3] [The Thrush] 1 score ([2] p.); 33 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For piano [in E]. [Part of suite: O'er Hill & Dale].
        [No. 4] [The] Thrush, 2nd Part, 1 score ([1] p.); 33 cm. Holograph in pencil, incomplete sketch. For piano [in E flat], [Part of suite: O'er Hill & Dale].